Willard Thompson Papers
Willard Thompson Papers
1966-1970
Thompson, Willard
2 linear ft.
Willard Thompson was an American professor of journalism and Dean of the General Extension Division and Summer Session (1969-1970), later Dean of the Summer School at the University of Minnesota. Papers include correspondence, meeting minutes and agendas, programs, lists and resolutions. The papers reflect Thompson’s role as Public Relations Committee Chairman for the Galaxy Conference (1969) and the subsequent Wingspread Conference (1976). Noteworthy among the correspondents because of his role in both conferences is Alexander N. Charters.
148705
Biographical History
Willard Thompson has been associated with the Department of Journalism at the University of Minnesota and served as the Dean of the General Extension Division and Summer Session of the University of Minnesota from 1969 to 1970. He is presently (1976) Dean of the Summer School at the same institution.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Willard Thompson Papers concern the Wingspread Conference and the Galaxy Conference, of which he was the Chairman of Public Relations from its conception in 1966 to its realization in December 1969. Headings under which the papers are arranged include the Education Writers Seminar, the Central Planning Group, the Advisory Committee, the Public Relations Committee, and the Wingspread Conference.
Related Material
The library holds a considerable number of collections related to adult and continuing education. Please refer to for a complete listing. In particular, the collections of the following people and organizations are most closely related:
Adult Education Association (AEA)
Council for the Continuing Education Unit (for Wingspread?)
Charters, Alexander N.
Coalition of Adult Education Organizations (CAEO)
Galaxy Conference
National University Extension Association (NUEA)
Subject and Genre Headings
Adult education; Charters, Alexander N.; Thompson, Willard L.; Galaxy Conference on Adult Education (1969: Washington, D.C.); Wingspread Conference on Adult Education (1976: Racine, Wis.); Adult education -- United States.; Public relations.; Correspondence.; Drafts (documents); Reports.; Minutes (administrative records); Notes (documents); Educators.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Willard Thompson
Inventory
The following is a simple BOX LIST. The collection has not yet been processed.
- Galaxy Conference
  - Advisory Committee, 1969 (Box 1)
  - Central Planning Group, 1967-1969 (Box 1)
  - General papers
    - 1966-1968 (Box 1)
    - 1969 (Box 1)
    - 1969-1970, undated (Box 2)
  - "Imperatives for Action"
    - 1969-1970 (Box 2)
    - 1969-1970 (Box 2)
  - Public relations, general, 1969 (Box 2)
  - Public Relations Committee
    - 1967 (Box 3)
    - 1968 (Box 3)
    - Jan 1969 - Jun 1969 (Box 3)
    - Jul 1969 - 1970 (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 3)
- Wingspread Conference
  - 1969-1970, 4 folders (Box 4)